link to codepen: https://codepen.io/bugbountychrisg8691/pen/QWNqWJN?editors=1100

1. What is Semantic HTML? 
HTML that gives meaning to the webpage instead of just presentation, i.e. when an HTML tag represent to the user and the browser what the enclosed data is

2. What is HTML used for? 
HTML handles the basic formating for the text and images on a webpage, tells the browser how to display the data

3. What is an attribute and where do we put it? 
An attribute contains information about a tag and it is placed in the starting tag

4. What is the h1 tag used for? How many times should I use it on a page?
An h1 tag is a "title" tag and once per page 

5. Name two tags that have required attributes
<a>, <img>

6. What do we put in the head of our HTML document? 
an html tag and a header tag and a title tag

7. What is an id? 
unique identifier

8. What elements can I add an id to? 
all but <base>, <head>, <html>, <meta>, <script>, <style>, <title>

9. How many times can I use the same id on a page? 
once

10. What is a class? 
identifier in a stylesheet

11. What elements can I add a class to? 
any

12. How many times can I use the same class on a page? 
infinite

13. How do I get my link to open in a new tab?
href="_blank"

14. What is the alt attribute in the image tag used for? 
alternative text for image

15. How do I reference an id?
#<id>

16. What is the difference between a section and a div
section is symantic and a grouping of content, div is not symantic without specifying a descriptive class. In simpler terms, a section is a container made up of divs as subcontainers.

17. What is CSS used for? 
styling

18. How to we select an element? Example - every h2 on the page
h2{
	...;
}

19. What is the difference between a class and an id? - Give me an example of when I might use each one
class is used to style similar objects together, and id is a unique identifier to be styled alone

20. How do we select classes in CSS?
.<class>

21. How do we select a p element with a single class of “human””?
p.human{
	...;
}

22. What is a parent child selector? When would this be useful? 
used to select all elements that are a part of a larger element; if you needed to select all <h2> elements of a <div>

23. How do you select all links within a div with the class of sidebar?
.sidebar div{
	...;
}

24. What is a pseudo selector?
represents the state of an element

25. What do we use the change the spacing between lines?
line-height

26. What do we use to change the spacing between letters?
letter-spacing

27. What do we use to to change everything to CAPITALS? lowercase? Capitalize?
text-transform:uppercase; text-transform:lowercase; text-transform:capitalize

28. How do I add a 1px border around my div that is dotted and black?
div{
	border:1px dotted black;
}

29. How do I select everything on the page? 
*{
	...;
}

30. How do I write a comment in CSS?
// for single line
/*...*/ for multiline

31. How do I find out what file I am in, when I am using the command line? 
pwd in powershell and linux terminal
cd in command prompt

32. Using the command line - how do I see a list of files/folders in my current folder?
ls

33. How do I remove a file via the command line? Why do I have to be careful with this? 
rm in powershell and linux terminal
del in command prompt; because there is no verification prompt it's just gone and not in your recycling bin, either

34. Why should I use version control? 
because it saves your work remotely, it helps when working with teams, 

35. How often should I commit to github?
once every couple hours

36. What is the command we would use to push our repo up to github? 
first time - git push -u origin <branch>
other - git push origin <branch>

37. Walk me through Lambda's git flow. 
fork
add TL as collaborator
clone - git clone <url>
branch - git checkout -b '<name>'
do your work
add work to git staging - git add <files>
give commit some info - git commit -m '<info>'
add commit to repo - git push -u origin <branch>
submit pull request


Stretch Questions

1. What is the difference between an inline element and a block element?
inline elements can have elements to left and right and respect their margins and padding, but not top and bottom and cannot have width or height attributes
block elements respect margins and padding of all surrounds elements, force a break after, and uses width of page if not specified 


2. What happens when an element is positioned absolutely? 
it is placed via coordinates of its' parent's location, if no parent then the top left of the page

3. How do I make an element take up only the amount of space it needs but also have the ability to give it a width? 
...{
	display:inline-block;
	width:...;
}

4. Name 3 elements that are diplay block by default, 2 elements that are display inline by default and 1 element that is display inline-block by default
block - <div>, <section>, <footer>
inline - <i>, <a>
inline-block - <button>

5. In your own words, explain the box model. What is the "fix" for the box model, in other words, how do we make all elements respect the width we've given them?


